<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>June 2021 Hackathon Week – Docs</title><link>https://modernappsninja.github.io/june2021hackathon_hw3657/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Docs on June 2021 Hackathon Week</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 18:34:25 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://modernappsninja.github.io/june2021hackathon_hw3657/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Hackathon Overview and Instructions</title><link>https://modernappsninja.github.io/june2021hackathon_hw3657/docs/courseintroduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 18:34:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://modernappsninja.github.io/june2021hackathon_hw3657/docs/courseintroduction/</guid><description>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#hackathon-week-overview">Hackathon Week Overview&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#schedule">Schedule&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#instructions">Instructions&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#report-an-issue---bug-or-feature-request----hackathon-qa-reporter-badge">Report an Issue - Bug or Feature Request &amp;ndash; Hackathon QA Reporter Badge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#validate-a-course-or-guide----hackathon-qa-validator-badge">Validate a course or guide &amp;ndash; Hackathon QA Validator Badge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#support-fellow-community-members----hackathon-support-provider-badge">Support fellow community members &amp;ndash; Hackathon Support Provider Badge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#resolve-an-issue-ticket---bug-or-feature-request----hackathon-triager-badge">Resolve an issue ticket - Bug or feature request &amp;ndash; Hackathon Triager Badge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#update-page-content----hackathon-content-committer-badge">Update Page Content &amp;ndash; Hackathon Content Committer Badge&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#contribute-new-content-or-features----hackathon-content-developer-bad">Contribute New Content or Features &amp;ndash; Hackathon Content Developer Bad&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="#thank-you-for-participating">Thank you for participating!&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="hackathon-week-overview">Hackathon Week Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hackathon week provides an opportunity to contribute to community, network with peers and learn and gain experience by opening and resolving issue tickets, make github commits with content updates, or even help with new site features!.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You do not need to be a developer, you can be a beginner with github, each step to participate has clear and simple instructions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>6 new limited edition Digital Badges will be available to participants who complete the simple requirements for each badge. In addition to earning the badges, each of the contributions you make will be reflected on your public github profile!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyone who opens an issue ticket, validates or updates content, contributes new content or features will be able to earn badges!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While many hackathons focus on building sample coding ideas that may or may not ever be used, in the ModernApps Learning hackathon you will contribute directly to production assets, and the hackathon badges will state clearly that you contributed to production assets!&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="prerequisites">Prerequisites&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>You must be a member of the ModernApps Ninja community to earn badges. Membership is completely free - to register, it is recommended that you complete the &lt;a href="https://modernapps.ninja/course/modernappsskills101_ms4043/">ModernApps Skills 101 course&lt;/a>, which which will walk you through membership registration and also how to (1) open an issue ticket and use a simple, browser based process to (2) post new files and (3) modify existing files on a public GitHub repository. These 3 skills are the 3 most important core skills you need to start actively participating and contributing to any git/github project!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also note per the details in the sections below, if you complete the &lt;a href="https://modernapps.ninja/course/modernappsskills101_ms4043/">ModernApps Skills 101 course&lt;/a> and submit an issue/feedback ticket during the hackathon week period, you will earn the Hackathon QA Contributor badge&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="schedule">Schedule&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Each contribution made in accordance with the instructions provided in this document, made during the hackathon timeframe, will be eligible towards earning Hackathon badges, per the requirements listed.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hackathon Participation/Contribution Timeframe
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Begins: 8:00 AM Pacific Time, 06/25/2021&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Concludes: 11:59 PM Pacific Time, 07/03/2021&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hackathon Event Schedule:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>8:00 AM Pacific Time, 06/25/2021
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hackathon Participation/Contribution Timeframe Begins&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://modernapps.ninja/event/srelive_6-25-21/">Hackathon Kickoff Zoom Call&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>After the kickoff call, a recording of the call will be posted to the &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/337vm0iwDF8">ModernApps Learning Youtube Page&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>8:00 AM Pacific time, 07/02/2021
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://modernapps.ninja/event/srelive_7-2-21/">ModernApps SRE Live! Hackathon Checkin Zoom Call&lt;/a>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Topics:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Review Hackathon Progress&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Review tickets for issues, feeback and pull requests&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Github Projects/Agile project planning&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Light retro&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>11:59 PM Pacific Time, 07/03/2021
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Hackathon Participation/Contribution Timeframe Concludes/Event Ends&lt;/li>
&lt;li>No contributions submitted after this time will be eligible for meeting requirements to earn the June 2021 Hackathon Badges&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="instructions">Instructions&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In future hackathons we intend to focus contribution efforts towards validating new courses, refreshing specific courses, or working towards specific features; However in the June 2021 hackathon, all valid bug reports, feature requests, feedback tickets, contributions to any course, guide or site page will be eligible towards completing digital badge requirements per the instructions in the following subsections.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It will be possible for earning up to 6 Digital Badges, each representing different types of participant activities listed below.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="report-an-issue---bug-or-feature-request----hackathon-qa-reporter-badge">Report an Issue - Bug or Feature Request &amp;ndash; Hackathon QA Reporter Badge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Any participant who reports a valid bug or feature request for any course, guide or other site page in the modernapps.ninja domain during the hackathon timeframe is eligible to request the Hackathon QA Reporter Badge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please keep the ticket number and the URL for the ticket opened as it will be needed to request your digital badge.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="validate-a-course-or-guide----hackathon-qa-validator-badge">Validate a course or guide &amp;ndash; Hackathon QA Validator Badge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To validate a course:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Go through any course and complete the requirements to earn the digital badge for completing that course&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Open a &lt;a href="https://github.com/ModernAppsNinja/modernappsninja.github.io/issues/new/choose">General Feedback&lt;/a> Issue Ticket and provide your feedback for the course. There is currently no specific format for the feedback, we would appreciate if you could in your own words share what you liked about the course, any problems or things you didnt like, any suggestions for course improvements or any other feedback about the course you may have.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>After you have completed these requirements, please keep the url to the digital badge you earned for completing the course, and the issue ticket number and URL for the ticket you used to submit your course feedback, as you will need these items to request your Hackathon digital badge.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="support-fellow-community-members----hackathon-support-provider-badge">Support fellow community members &amp;ndash; Hackathon Support Provider Badge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you help provide support to resolve a question or issue for another community member during the Hackathon timeframe, you will be eligible for the Hackathon Support Provider Badge&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It does not matter in which forum you provided this support, as long as you helped to provide an answer or other support to resolve another member&amp;rsquo;s question/issue. You may typically find users seeking support in the issue tickets on any repo in the ModernAppsNinja org, in the Members team discussion board, or on the #modernappsninja slack channel in the VMware Code slack domain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To request this badge, please keep the ticket number/url or a screenshot or other record of the conversation where you helped resolve another members question.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="resolve-an-issue-ticket---bug-or-feature-request----hackathon-triager-badge">Resolve an issue ticket - Bug or feature request &amp;ndash; Hackathon Triager Badge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For any open issue ticket (not including user support tickets) on any site in the modernapps.ninja domain or ModernAppsNinja github org, if you provide a resolution for that issue, you will be eligible to request the Hackathon triager badge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please note that you may not have the permissions required to close an issue ticket, so you do not need to close the ticket. For the ticket you resolve, please add a note to that ticket that includes the details of what you did to resolve the issue, and include the URL to any pull requests/commits or any other item you may have updated to resolve the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To request this badge, you will need to provide the URL to the ticket that you resolved as well as the URL for any pull requests related to resolving the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="update-page-content----hackathon-content-committer-badge">Update Page Content &amp;ndash; Hackathon Content Committer Badge&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you make any update to any page on any ModernApps Learning course or lab guide, you will be eligible for the Hackathon Content Committer Badge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every ModernApps Learning Course and Lab Guide page has a link on the right navigation bar to &lt;code>Edit this page&lt;/code>. If you see any problems or improvements you can make to any page, please click the edit this page link, make and submit your suggested edit, and you will be eligible for the Hackathon Content Commiter Badge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To request this badge, you will need to provide the URL to a PullRequest or Commit where you provided an update to a ModernApps Learning Page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="contribute-new-content-or-features----hackathon-content-developer-bad">Contribute New Content or Features &amp;ndash; Hackathon Content Developer Bad&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you provide a new course, lab guide, or submit your technical/educational blog to the tutorials page, you will be eligible for the Hackathon Content Developer Badge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Tutorials page on modernapps learning provides a collection of links and descriptions to Technical content that is focused on providing education about a technical product or concept related to application modernization and VMware Tanzu. Most tutorials are blogs, but could be a white paper, webinar, external course/workshop or any freely accessible public content that provides technical education on a relevant technical topic. ModernApps learning only provides a description and link to your blog - your content may be hosted on any publically available website and should be free and not require any charge or payment to access. Tutorial topics do not need to be about a Tanzu or other product and may instead focus on learning technical concepts, skills and knowlege related to infrastructure and application modernization. All submitted tutorials must include only respectful and appropriate/professional content and are subject to approval by ModernApps Learning Admins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://modernapps.ninja/blog/adding-a-new-blog-post/">Please Click Here for instructions on submitting a Tutorial&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you would like to create a new course or lab guide, please &lt;a href="https://github.com/ModernAppsNinja/modernappsninja.github.io/issues/new/choose">open a Support Request issue ticket on the ModernAppsNinja/modernappsninja.github.io repository&lt;/a> and an administrator will respond to you to assist in creating your course or lab guide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To request this badge, you will need to provide the URL to the Tutorial listing on the ModernApps Learning tutorials page, or the URL to the pullRequest you used to submit your tutorial.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thank-you-for-participating">Thank you for participating!&lt;/h2></description></item></channel></rss>